Speaker: Here are ten top tips to make your car journey safe.
Tip one
Plan your journey.
Look at a map and plan where to stop on the way.
Tip two
Check your car.
Is it ready for a long journey?
Do it yourself or take it to a garage.
Tip three
Listen to traffic information on the radio,
or check on the internet, before you start your journey.
Tip four
Take a map with you in the car,
or have a map app on your phone
– satnav (or GPS) isn’t always right.
Tip five
Take bottles of water.
People are often thirsty on long car journeys.
Tip six
If you have children in the car, take books, games, and tablets with you.
Then the children can watch videos or read.
When children are quiet, the driver is less distracted.
Tip seven
Check that all the passengers in the car have their seat belt on.
Tip eight
Check that you have petrol.
Don’t wait until your petrol tank is nearly empty
before you look for a petrol station.
Tip nine
After driving for two hours,
stop for fifteen minutes.
Have a snack, and get some fresh air.
If you’re very tired, have a coffee
or a drink with caffeine.
Finally, tip ten.
This is very, very important.
Don’t use your phone.
Phoning and texting are very dangerous because you don’t concentrate on the road.
Have a safe journey!